<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Manifesto on SuperHeroWiki</title>
    <link>http://localhost/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Manifesto on SuperHeroWiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="http://localhost/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduzione</title>
      <link>http://localhost/preparation/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/preparation/intro/</guid>
      <description>Authors: Stefano Ivancich
Academic books prepare you for fancy research, they will make you a better software engineer, but they&amp;rsquo;re not sufficient for interviews. You need to prepare with real interview questions and learn their patterns. It&amp;rsquo;s about developing a fresh algorithm, not memorizing existing problems. At most of the top tech companies (and many other companies), algorithm and coding problems form the largest component of the interview process. The interviewer is looking to evaluate your ability to solve algorithmic problems you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen before, to ask the right questions to clarify ambiguity and explain your thought process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manifesto</title>
      <link>http://localhost/community/manifesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/community/manifesto/</guid>
      <description>Cos’è Superhero Valley: SuperHero Valley è una community nata nell’Ottobre 2020 con l’obiettivo di instaurare un ponte tra l’università e le grandi aziende nel campo dell’informatica. In altre nazioni è comune, durante il periodo universitario, seguire corsi tarati per sostenere tech interviews e svolgere internships in grandi aziende. Queste attività sono pressoché inesistenti e sconosciute in Italia. Ottenere un’offerta di internship, o anche una posizione Full Time, dalle aziende della Silicon Valley non è impresa facile senza la dovuta preparazione.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrivere il CV</title>
      <link>http://localhost/preparation/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/preparation/cv/</guid>
      <description>Una delle domande più frequenti delle persone che partecipano ai nostri talk è &amp;ldquo;Come posso scrivere il mio CV&amp;rdquo;? Durante i nostri talk abbiamo più volte affrontato questo argomento, in questa sezione vogliamo riassumere tutti i consigli che ci sono stati dati nel corso del tempo.
Una volta che hai scritto il tuo CV non esitare a inviarlo sul nostro gruppo discord (canale #cv-review) per avere suggerimenti e consigli per migliorarlo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to find good companies</title>
      <link>http://localhost/preparation/find_companies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/preparation/find_companies/</guid>
      <description>Authors: Stefano Ivancich
In 2023 you have a 3% chance of getting an offer from any application, with 50 applications you have 87% chance of getting at least one job offer. Trust in the law of large numbers. Send out applications to more places than you’re currently planning. You can always &amp;ldquo;pause&amp;rdquo; or simply cancel the interview process with some companies. Schedule your favorite companies last. Get interview practice with the places you aren’t as excited about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding Interview</title>
      <link>http://localhost/preparation/coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/preparation/coding/</guid>
      <description>Introduction - Work In Progress!!! Overview of a Coding Interview Technical Assessment Timeline Links STUDY PLANS:
Tech Interview HandBook (GitHub): consigli, materiale per studiare e link ad esercizi per prepararsi alle interview InterviewBit Preparation: buona scaletta degli argomenti per la preparazione Leetcode Study Plans TEORIA (WEBSITES):
Algorithms for Competitive Programming Coding Interview University 14 Patterns to Ace Any Coding Interview Question 25 Patterns you must know Grokking the coding interview (a pagamento, ma molto consigliato) TEORIA (LIBRI)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>System Design Inteview</title>
      <link>http://localhost/preparation/system_design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/preparation/system_design/</guid>
      <description> Introduction - Work in Progress!!! Links TEORIA (WEBSITES)
System Design Primer Small System Design Course by Hiredintech System Design Interview Web API Design Best Practices Learn about Non-Abstract Large Systems Design (NALSD) Latency Numbers Everyone Should Know Guide to crack the System Design interview (Presenta un buon template per la risoluzione di system design problems) TEORIA (VIDEO)
Design a Distributed System in One Hour (NALSD) System Design interview concepts in 10 mins </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behavioral Interview</title>
      <link>http://localhost/preparation/behavioral/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/preparation/behavioral/</guid>
      <description>Authors: Stefano Ivancich
During a job interview, one of the interviewer&amp;rsquo;s task is to explore the way you handled a &amp;ldquo;complex&amp;rdquo; situation in the past (preferably at the workplace). Let&amp;rsquo;s see how to prepare a stellar behavioral interview using the STAR-L method.
Example of behavioral questions: Describe a time when you disagreed with a team member. How did you resolve the problem? Describe a time when you faced a block at work and how you solved it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contatti</title>
      <link>http://localhost/community/contatti/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/community/contatti/</guid>
      <description>Gruppo Discord: È il cuore della community, viene utilizzato per tutte le comunicazioni, per confrontarsi e scambiarsi opinioni. È organizzato in canali, alcuni di essi sono canali vocali in cui è possibile organizzare mock interview o esercizi di gruppo.
Calendario Google: utile per non perdere gli eventi organizzati da Superhero Valley e trovarli sincronizzati direttamente nella vostra app calendario preferita.
Gruppo Telegram: gruppo di sola lettura in cui scriviamo solamente le comunicazioni più importanti.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eventi</title>
      <link>http://localhost/community/eventi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/community/eventi/</guid>
      <description>Prossimi eventi in programma Controlla sul canale #annoucements su Discord, sul Calendario e su Telegram (Trovi i link qui).
Se invece vuoi vedere gli eventi passati puoi visionare l&amp;rsquo;apposita pagina nel nostro sito.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>http://localhost/community/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/community/faq/</guid>
      <description>- Le internship sono pagate? Si, le internship in tutte le grandi aziende sono pagate. Oltre allo stipendio mensile alcune aziende possono anche offrire un bonus &amp;ldquo;relocation&amp;rdquo; e il pagamento dei voli per raggiungere la città dove si trovano gli uffici.
- Come posso prepararmi alle coding interview? Per prepararsi alle coding interview è necessario avere una conoscenza di base di algoritmi e strutture dati, nella nostra wiki trovi molte risorse per ripassare o studiare questi argomenti.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miscellaneous</title>
      <link>http://localhost/link_utili/miscellaneous/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/link_utili/miscellaneous/</guid>
      <description> Lista di possibili domande da fare al colloquio tecnico Best practices for ML Watch technical mocking interviews Google Virtual Student Series 175 Powerful verbs that will make your CV awesome An Algorithm for passing Programming Interviews Topics you can&amp;rsquo;t skip for interview preparation using Leetcode List of upcoming competitive programming competitions Grokking the * Interview bundle ad accesso illimitato a tutti i corsi Grokking (a pagamento) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ricerca Internship</title>
      <link>http://localhost/preparation/ricerca_internships/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/preparation/ricerca_internships/</guid>
      <description>Elenco aziende che organizzano internship Azienda Link Google https://careers.google.com/ Nvidia https://nvidia.wd5.myworkdayjobs.com/ Mozilla https://careers.mozilla.org/ Facebook https://www.facebook.com/careers/ Apple https://jobs.apple.com/en-us/search?team=internships-STDNT-INTRN Amazon https://www.amazon.jobs/ Microsoft https://careers.microsoft.com/ Jetbrains https://www.jetbrains.com/careers/jobs/ Adobe https://www.adobe.com/careers.html Linkedin https://careers.linkedin.com/ Bloomberg https://careers.bloomberg.com/ Klarna https://www.klarna.com/careers/ Ubisoft https://www.ubisoft.com/en-us/company/careers DeepMind https://deepmind.com/careers Two Sigma https://www.twosigma.com/careers/ Yelp https://www.yelp.careers/us/en SpaceX https://www.spacex.com/careers/index.html Tesla https://www.tesla.com/it_IT/careers Cisco https://jobs.cisco.com/ IBM https://www.ibm.com/it-it/employment/ Bandai https://www.bandainamcostudios.com/en/careers/ Blizzard https://careers.blizzard.com/global/en Unity https://careers.unity.com/ EA https://www.ea.com/careers Oracle https://www.oracle.com/it/corporate/careers/ Sony https://boards.greenhouse.io/sonyinteractiveentertainmentplaystation Nintendo https://www.nintendo.it/Chi-siamo/Jobs/Jobs-Lavorare-in-Nintendo-757078.html Cloudflare https://www.cloudflare.com/it-it/careers/ Spotify https://www.spotifyjobs.com/ Bending Spoons https://bendingspoons.com/careers.html Lockheed Martin https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strumenti Coop</title>
      <link>http://localhost/link_utili/strumenti/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost/link_utili/strumenti/</guid>
      <description>Strumenti utili per la preparazione in gruppo o per le mock interviews.
Code Editors: Leetcode Playground* (NB: verificare che l&amp;rsquo;URL di invito finisca in /live) Codeshare (Settate sintassi Python e tab indentation 4 per evitare problemi di compatibilità con InterviewBit/LeetCode) Whiteboards: WebWhiteBoard* (Click rotellina per muoversi sul foglio) NotebookCast (Settare whiteboard custom size a 4000x4000) Excalidraw (Click rotellina per muoversi sul foglio) Google Jamboard [*] Consigliato!!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
